gradireland.com 2019-04-28

# Privacy policy – GTI Media | Group GTI

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you engage with one of our websites or services. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.

## Changes to data protection law

From the 25th of May 2018, we will be processing your personal data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). Up until that point we will continue to process your personal data in accordance with the existing Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA). This notice is written to comply with both the DPA and the GDPR.

## Who are we?

We are GTI Media, a company which is part of our parent company Group GTI. Our main address is:

**The Fountain Building, Howbery Park  
Benson Lane  
Wallingford  
Oxfordshire   
OX10 8BA, UK**

You can contact us by post at the above address, or via email at [data.protection@groupgti.com](mailto:data.protection@groupgti.com) or by telephone on +44 (0)1491 826262.

## What personal data do we collect?

We request certain personal information from you in order for us to assist you in providing information relating to career options, job opportunities, undergraduate and postgraduate study options and other related services such as employer-sponsored events and competitions aimed at post-sixteen, graduate and postgraduate job seekers. This may include CVs and personal contact details.

Personal data request may also contain “special category data” as defined in the GDPR, or “sensitive personal data” as defined in the DPA. In both cases this may include racial or ethnic origin, sexual orientation and health (ie. whether you are registered disabled). You can decide whether you wish to share this information with us. Not sharing this information does not prevent you from registering or using our services.

We also on occasion may request information related to social mobility which may be required by an employee for an event, course provider or employer opportunity.

Through the use of cookies and other similar technology we may record your interaction with our websites and systems to help improve the delivery of our services. In addition as part of our security measures we may also record the IP address from which you are engaging with us.

## Where else may we get data from?

### Associated partners

For our GTI media websites, for example targetjobs.co.uk, targetcareers.co.uk and gradireland.com, we sometimes obtain personal data from third parties. In such circumstances we are reliant on the third party supplier’s assurances that they have the appropriate legal basis for processing and transferring this data. We record the source of this data so you can ask us at any time from where we got your personal details and object to the processing should you believe your data was inappropriately transferred. 

### Inspiring Futures

Inspiring Futures Limited provide careers advice to school-age students and are a wholly owned subsidiary of GTI Media. As such, in relation to personal data collected via Futurewise and other related services provided by Inspiring Futures Limited, both GTI Media and Inspiring Futures are joint data controllers with respect to personal data collected from their profiling service and career related events.

## Why do we collect this information?

We collect information about you in order to provide you with the best careers advice possible tailored to your specific preferences or experience. The information is also necessary for us and employers to match you against any opportunities that they have.

For employer sponsored events and awards we may use the information collected to contact you in relation to those opportunities that fit your profile.

In addition, we sometimes use the anonymous personal data (ie. with all personal identifiers removed) for the purposes of research, industry trend reporting and for our own planning purposes and future developments.

## Where is my information stored?

Your information is either stored in the databases for our websites or other systems, all of which are based within the European Union (specifically the UK).

## What do we do with your information?

The personal information you provide helps us to offer more tailored advice and opportunities depending on your preferences. Our aim is to provide you with only content relevant to you. This includes any careers advice, job opportunities, information about our employer-sponsored events, and our awards events that may be sent to you via email or other means (where you have provided the appropriate information). You may unsubscribe to these emails or change your profile information at any time either via the site or through the link provided at the bottom of each email.

To be more specific your information may be used in one or more of the following ways:

  * To communicate with you in the delivery of our services including client opportunities, sponsored events or employer-sponsored competitions.
  * To contact you directly about your interest in attending an employer-sponsored event or entering an employer-sponsored awards competition.
  * To notify you of any changes to terms and conditions or policy changes.
  * To help us improve our services and its delivery to you.
  * To conduct market research activities.
  * To provide you with relevant advice and career options relevant to you.
  * To carry out our obligations in relation to any contracts between you and GTI Media.
  * To allow you to better engage with the interactive and personalised services on our websites, apps and systems.
  * In an aggregated and anonymised form, use the data to plan new products, manage our relationship with our clients, and also improve existing products.
  * To facilitate any social media sharing functionality and authentication.
  * To resolve complaints and data access requests in accordance with data protection law.
  * For the facilitation of any legal obligations or defend any court actions that we may have.

## Who we might share your data with?

### Our group of companies

In order to deliver the best possible integrated careers advice and services to you, from time to time we may transfer your personal details between our websites. This may on occasion be across different companies within our group. Before doing so we conduct a Data Protection Impact Assessment in order to ensure that any such transfers do not impact your rights. You may object to your data being processed in this manner by contacting us using the details above.

### Our service providers

For the purposes of sending emails and maintaining engagement information we will maintain a secure copy of your personal data with our service partners whom provide the facilities to email users based on their preference criteria and track engagement. Access to this data is strictly controlled and we remain the data controller.

### Employers and sponsors

In addition, the CVs you submit directly to us will be accessible by our Search team (who recruit on behalf of employers) working for our sister company GTI Recruiting Solutions (also known as TARGETrecruit) as well as potential employers.

Along with your CV, personal details contained in your profile might be shared with potential employers where you have expressed an interest in joining or attending one of their careers events or entering their sponsored competition run on their behalf by GTI.

Your profile details (with the exception of any special categories of personal data as defined by Article 9 of the GDPR) including contact information will also be supplied to employers if you have agreed to be contacted directly by the employer or course provider for a particular role, course or event via our direct message functionality. Employers or course providers should only contact you with respect of that particular role or event in each instance, and you have the right to request that the Employer stop contacting you by getting in touch with them directly.

For TARGETjobs events that you have attended we may also share your personal details including your CV with employers at the event so that they may contact you directly about opportunities with them.

### Government, legal or regulatory authorities

GTI may be required to share your personal information with certain public or legal authorities where there is a legislative obligation to do so.

## Automated processing and profiling

We use the information you provide to make automated decisions solely in the capacity of delivering you content based on your stated preferences. Personal data may be matched against potential vacancies in order to provide relevance to the content and information we provide you. However you have at all times access to all available vacancies and may change your preferences to amend what content or vacancies are filtered.

There are no automated decision making processes that would impact you as a result of any automated processing. No judgements or decisions are made of an individual’s suitability for a particular role as a result of any processing that may take place.

## Legal basis for processing your data

The legal basis for processing under both the DPA and GDPR across our sites are outlined in the table below:

**– This table will scroll horizontally on smaller devices ******

 ** **

### Consent

On occasion we may process you data on the basis of consent (such as sensitive data), or the sending of promotional or marketing material not related to careers, job opportunities, or employer-sponsored events and competitions. In addition, where there is a facility to link to your Social network.

### Contract

It may be necessary for GTI to process your data in order to fulfil a contract with you such as sending your CV to an employer or recruitment consultant for a particular role you have applied for or are interested in. We also may need to process your data if you are an employer or school for the purposes of fulfilling our contractual obligations to you in the delivery of a service.

### Legitimate interest

GTI may also process your data when it is in our legitimate interest to do so and in doing so it does not override any of your data protection rights. Our legitimate interests include:

  * ensuring the security and integrity of our services and ensuring that our systems such as websites and apps work properly;
  * selling and supplying services to our clients;
  * protecting clients, employees and other individuals (including yourself) and maintaining their safety, health and welfare;
  * the promotion, marketing and advertising our products and services;
  * sending promotional communications tailored to your preferences from our clients in relation to your career;
  * understanding our clients and your behaviour, activities, preferences, and needs to deliver a better quality and custom experience;
  * improving existing products and services and developing new products and services;
  * the handling client and your contacts, queries, complaints or disputes; and
  * fulfilling our duties to our clients, yourself, colleagues, shareholders and other stakeholders.

You have the right to object to the processing of your data under legitimate interest should you feel that such legal basis is not warranted or feel that it overrides any of the rights that you may have.

## How long do we keep your information for?

**– This table will scroll horizontally on smaller devices ******

 ** **

## Your rights over your information

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.

You can also ask us to give you a copy of the information and to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.

To submit a request by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided above.

In addition to the above you have the following rights under GDPR:

  * The right to ask what personal data is held, subject to a fee (currently £10), free from the 25th May 2018.
  * The right to ask to update and correct any out of date or incorrect personal data that we hold free of charge.
  * The right to erasure of personal data where consent is the only legal basis for processing and that consent has been withdrawn.
  * The right to data portability in the sense that personal data provided directly by the data subject is exportable in an open format like CSV where the legal basis for processing is based on either contract or consent.
  * The right to restrict or object to the processing of your personal data where:
    * You contest the accuracy of the personal data and the accuracy needs to be verified;
    * You object to the processing under legitimate interest grounds and consideration needs to be made whether GTI’s legitimate interest overrides that of the individuals;
    * The processing was unlawful and you request restricted processing over erasure.

You can withdraw consent at any time where consent has been relied upon. If consent is the sole legal basis for processing, we will stop processing the data after the consent is withdrawn. The data will then be placed in a restricted processing mode until you have asked to exercise your right to erasure or the personal data falls outside stated retention period (whichever comes first).

## Our communications with you

We will periodically communicate with you by email, post, telephone or device notifications for the purposes of delivering our services to you. The legal purpose for which is under the legitimate interest provision under both GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR).

However, should you be concerned about the content of these communications (such as unwanted marketing communications or simply want to change the way we communicate with you please log into your profile on the relevant website and change your preferences, or use the relevant unsubscribe link. Alternatively you can contact us by telephone or letter at the details provided above.

## Changes to this privacy notice

From time to time we may need to make changes to this notice. We will attempt to inform you of any changes that are made either through both email notifications or through associated websites. This privacy notice was last updated on the 9th of September 2018.

## Your right to complain

If you have a complaint about our use of your information you can do so with the relevant supervisory authority within the EU to which you are a resident, whom may refer the complaint to the UK supervisory authority. 

Complaints in the UK can be made to the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at [www.ico.org/concerns](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/) or write to them at:

**Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF**

********
